Everybody dies. And that's fucked up.
The Monkey is a horror, comedy film directed by Osgood Perkins.
When twin brothers find a mysterious wind-up monkey, a series
of outrageous deaths tear their family apart.
Twenty-five years later, the monkey begins a new killing spree
forcing the estranged brothers to confront the cursed toy.
Hal / Bill, played by Theo James.
Lois, played by Tatiana Maslany.
Young Hal / Young Bill, played by Christian Convery.
Petey, played by Colin O'Brien.
Captain Petey Shelborn, played by Adam Scott.
Ted, played by Elijah Wood.
The Monkey is a 2025 American comedy horror film
written and directed by Osgood Perkins.
Based on Stephen King's 1980 short story, the film stars Theo James in a dual role as twin brothers whose lives
are turned upside down by a cursed toy monkey that causes random horrific deaths around them.
Tatiana Maslany, Christian Convery, Colin O'Brien, Rohan Campbell,
Sarah Levy, Adam Scott, and Elijah Wood also star.
The Monkey was theatrically released in the United
States by Neon on February 21, 2025.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and has grossed
$68.9 million worldwide against a budget of $10–11 million.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship,
shotgun, supernatural, drums, harpoon.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.